# Edward John Bayliss

Phone: +44 7768 046582 E-mail: edward.bayliss@icloud.com 7 Swan Lane, Abbots Bromley, Rugeley Staffordshire, WS15 3BX

## **PROFILE**

A graduate of the Cable and Wireless Worldwide Apprenticeship Scheme, awarded 'Apprentice of the Year' and 'Customer Service Award' with nine years' experience in a real-time operations environment. Well respected by team members, punctual, reliable, enthusiastic and committed to furthering a career in telecommunications. Motivated to maximise opportunities both in and outside of work. Flexible and willing to assist others at short notice.

# WORK EXPERIENCE



## **Vodafone Group**

# Role: 3<sup>rd</sup> Line Core IP and Security

June 2017 – Present

I currently work to provide 3<sup>rd</sup> line support required to resolve complex faults and support high level provide and change issues. This is done via a 24/7 on-call support basis as well as being available for hardware and software upgrades. I provide approval and acceptance of new products for multiple technologies and work closely with multiple vendors to support the core network in the most cost-effective manner. The role required me to be well versed with writing in python and has seen me write multiple programs to support 2nd line teams and automate monitoring and security of the network. Most recently the role has seen me mentor and take responsibility for three of the new Vodafone apprentices sharing my knowledge of both networking and cyber security.

The role has provided me with the following key skills:

The ability to troubleshoot and solve issues within provider networks to a CCNP-SP level with diagnostic, testing and install knowledge. Hands on experience making configuration changes on a live network with MPLS, ISIS, BGP, QoS, VPN's and other protocols along with extensive exposure to network monitoring tools such as Netcool and SMARTS and the ability to provide solutions with my own designs.

- · Juniper (JUNOS)
- E Series BNG's
- MX Series
- · Cisco (IOS)
- 2900 Series
- 3600, 3700, 3800 Series
- 7200 Series
- · Cisco (IOS XR)
- CRS Series
- 12000 Series
- 9000 Series
- 2960's, 3850's 6500's
- · Alcatel (TiMOS)
- 7750's
- Linux.

- · Multiprotocol Label Switching (MPLS)
- · Border Gateway Protocol (BGP)
- · Intermediate System Intermediate System (IS-IS)
- · Quality of Service (QoS)
- · Virtual Private Network (VPN)
- · Open Shortest Path First (OSPF)
- · Virtual Routing Forwarding (VRF)
- · Resource Reservation Protocol (RSVP)
- · Multi-tasking
- · Planned maintenance tasks
- · Proactive monitoring
- · Raising change requests
- · Major Incident Management
- · Training others.

# **Vodafone Group**



**Role: Core IP Senior Engineer (Shift)** 

August 2015 - June 2017

I worked within a real-time operations environment supporting complex multi-technology solutions and incident management on a global scale. The role is customer facing and requires an ability to fault find at 1<sup>st</sup> and 2<sup>nd</sup> line within SLA's and deadlines. I was responsible for the core of the Vodafone's IPVPN, MSP and Internet networks. I work with multiple equipment vendors such as Cisco, Alcatel and Juniper. I am familiar with a telecommunications NOC environment and I have continued to support new and upcoming technologies as well as currently holding SC & BC security clearance.

The role has provided me with key skills:

The ability to use and configure Juniper, (JUNOS) Alcatel (TiMOS) and Cisco (IOS & XR) to a high level Hands on experience with multiple vendors and protocols along with extensive exposure to network monitoring tools.

# **Vodafone Group**



**Role: Core IP Support Engineer (Shift)** 

**August 2014 - August 2015** 

### **Role Purpose:**

The role provided me with an introduction to Juniper (JUNOS) Alcatel (TiMOS) and Cisco (IOS & XR) I worked in an assure environment supporting 1<sup>st</sup> and 2<sup>nd</sup> line monitoring. I performed planned outage, maintenance and upgrade work on Juniper, Cisco and Alcatel device.

## **Vodafone Group**



**Role: RTO Associate Engineer (Shift)** 

**February 2013 – August 2014** 

## **Role Purpose:**

The role provided me with experience in IP & data, as well as being educated to CCNA level in the live network within the Ex Cable and Wireless Worldwide network. I gained working experience and knowledge of network infrastructure and the NOC environments mostly in the transmission environment providing me with a thorough knowledge of PDH, SDH, DWDM and OTN technologies.

# Cable and Wireless Worldwide

Cable&Wireless Worldwide

**Role: RTO Apprentice Engineer (Days)** 

August 2010 - February 2013

#### **Role Purpose:**

I joined as part of the Cable and Wireless Worldwide Apprenticeship Scheme within real-time operations, learning to support incident management and develop customer service skills. I was able to manage my workload with education in order to gain my qualifications and develop myself as a network engineer.

# **QUALIFICATIONS**

# **Telecommunications Courses and Certifications:**

2012 - BTEC Level 3 Diploma in Professional Competence for ICT and Telecoms Professionals.

2012 - Advanced Level Apprenticeship in IT & Telecommunications.

## **Vendor Courses:**

Infinera DTN - Turn up and Test Ciena 6200 - Turn up and Test Juniper MX Series – BNG Configuration Nokia 7750 – Service Provider

# **EDUCATION**

# A/S Level (Walton High Sixth Form)

Total of 2 qualifications all A to C including Information Technology (IT)

# GCSE (Fair Oak Business and Enterprise College)

Total of 11 qualifications all A\* to C including English, Math's and Sciences

# **INTERESTS**

## **Scouting**

I am a committed member of the Scouting movement, and I am the District Leader for The Uttoxeter Network and also a local Scout Leader for the village I live in. This is a respected voluntary position which holds large responsibility for other members.

## Rock Climbing, Caving and Mountaineering

I have completed multiple climbing courses in order to broaden my knowledge and experience. I am currently working towards the Mountain Leader Award with the British Mountain Training Association. I also have trips to Italy climbing, along with a 10 day expedition to Berger Cave in France.

# REFERENCES

Available on request.